Now if you remember this whole mindset discussion on maximizing value for the client,
إذا كنت تتذكر ما تم مناقشته فيما يتعلق بفكرة تعظيم القيمة للعميل،
remember that the client is running this project in order to get some value out of it.
تذكر أن العميل يدير هذا المشروع بهدف الحصول على مردود منه.
But they want to balance this value with the required amount of time and money,
ولكنه يرغب في الموازنة بين المقدار المطلوب من الوقت والمال،
that's why it becomes important to actively look out for
لذلك من المهم البحث بفاعلية
ways to work efficiently in the project.
عن طرق للعمل بشكل أكثر كفاءة في المشروع.
Client may themselves not be conscious of what to prioritize and
قد لا يكون العميل على دراية بما يجب تحديد أولوياته
how to bring that implicant balance in order for the overall project to be efficient.
وكيفية تحقيق التوازن الضمني من أجل جعل المشروع ككل أكثر فاعلية.
But that's why they hired you.
ولهذا قام بالاستعانة بك.
They would assume that you would guide them
إنه يفترض أنك سوف تقوم بتوجيهه
wherever you see areas of how to be most efficient,
في المجالات حيث تكون أكثر فاعلية،
so that they can achieve an optimal output with an optimal amount of time and money.
حتى يحصل على مخرجات مثالية في وقت مثالي وبتكلفة مثالية.
Now let's look at some areas where one can bring efficiency in a client's project.
دعونا الآن نلقي نظرة على بعض الأمور التي قد تحقق الكفاءة في مشروع العميل.
First of all, it's important to pick the right tools,
أولًا، من المهم اختيار الأدوات المناسبة
to do the work that you have to do.
للقيام بالعمل المطلوب منك.
These tools could be caught by the off-the-shelf tools,
يمكن توفير تلك الأدوات من ما هو متاح بالفعل،
which would be either big or free.
والتي ستكون إما كبيرة أو مجانية.
These tools could either avoid reinventing the wheel
تجنبك هذه الأدوات إعادة اختراع العجلة
by already providing a workflow that we're looking to build,
من خلال توفير سير العمل الذي نتطلع إلى إنشائه
or they could just help get work done faster.
أو قد تساعد في إنجاز العمل بشكل أسرع.
For example, if the client wants to build a nice front end for a website,
على سبيل المثال، إذا أراد العميل إنشاء واجهة مميزة للصفحة،
you could just use a front-end framework like foundation,
يمكنك الاستعانة بواجهة من لتكون الأساس،
that could avoid all the heavy lifting to build a nice front-end.
وتجنب كل المجهود لبناء واحدة جديدة.
Or you can use an existing template and just customize it to suit the client's needs.
أو يمكنك استخدام نموذج متوفر وتعديله فقط ليلائم احتياجات العميل.
Some of the tools that you find to be optimal may not be available for free,
قد لا تتوفر بعض النماذج بالمجان
but the client may just be happy to pay for them
ولكن قد يرحب العميل بالدفع مقابلها،
if they bring in significant impact on productivity.
إذا كان لها تأثير كبير على الإنتاجية.
Now, another area to bring in efficiency is
والآن، هناك مجال آخر لتحقيق الكفاءة هو
your wisdom to optimize the sequence of workstreams.
حكمتك في الوصول لأفضل تسلسل لمسارات العمل.
For example, you could prioritize working on
على سبيل المثال، يمكنك تحديد أولويات العمل على
modules that could be reused later in the project.
الوحدات التي يمكن إعادة استخدامها في المشروع لاحقًا.
Some modules may be dependent on other modules,
قد تعتمد بعض الوحدات على وحدات أخرى،
so you could prioritize the dependencies so that you
حتى تتمكن من تحديد أولويات التبعية
have them when you work with the modules that need them.
لتحصل عليها وقت احتياجك.
Now, it's important to note that this list of areas
من المهم الإشارة إلى أن هذه القائمة الخاصة بمناطق
to bring inefficiency is not exhaustive.
تحقيق عدم الكفاءة ليست شاملة.
It is important to be on the lookout on how you can bring
عليك أن تكون متيقظًا لمناطق
inefficiency for the client's project depending on the project's context.
عدم الكفاءة في المشروع الخاص بالعميل وفق محتوى المشروع.
Again, keep in mind that the client may not be
مرة أخرى، ضع في اعتبارك أن العميل قد لا يكون
proactive enough to make these optimizations,
استباقي بما يكفي لإجراء هذه التحسينات،
even if they're technically qualified to do so.
حتى لو كان مؤهلًا تقنيًا للقيام بذلك.
Since you are working on the project,
بما أنك تعمل في المشروع،
it's important for you to determine how the entire project can be driven
من الضروري أن تحدد كيفية إدارة المشروع بأكمله
most efficiently to result in optimal value for the client's investment in it.
بأكثر الطرق كفاءة لتحقيق النتيجة المثلى لاستثمار العميل فيه.
But while you do that,
ولكن أثناء قيامك بهذا الأمر
it's important to communicate that to the client.
من الضروري التواصل مع العميل.
Remember that communication discussion.
تذكر أن أفضل تواصل هو النقاش.
It's ideal if you communicate to the client in a manner
من المهم التواصل مع العميل بطريقة
that they understand what value the optimization brings,
تمكنه من فهم قيمة التحسين المقترح،
so that they can appreciate your contribution in bringing up that optimization.
حتى يقدر المساهمة المقدمة لهذا التحسين.